If you're a beginner trying to make
money selling digital products, then
this video is for you. A lot of times
what beginners need is not some super
complex business strategy. They just
need a very simple plan to make their
first few sales online. Because once you
actually make your first dollar online,
everything changes. You start believing
that you can actually do this. You gain
that confidence you need to keep scaling
your business. So that's exactly what
I'm going to show you in this video. A
step-by-step tutorial on how to create a
simple digital product with AI and start
selling it online. All without spending
a dime to create it, building website,
or running ads. What I'm about to show
you isn't flashy. It's actually pretty
boring. And that is good because it's
actually the boring things that makes
you money. I've made over $2.2 million
doing this myself and I've taught
thousands of students to do the same. So
I know it works if you apply it and take
action. So if you enjoy this type of
content and you want me to make more,
then let me know by tapping the like
button and let's get right into the
video. Now, a quick disclaimer is that
the goal of this video is to help you
make your first dollar online, not to
make 10k per month or millions of
dollars. Because even though that is
possible, the steps required to build a
10k per month or more business naturally
becomes more complex. That's why if
you're just getting started, you should
start simple, gain the confidence, then
slowly add those things to build a 10k
per month business. And obviously I
cannot make any income claims or
guarantees here, so please don't take
this video as me promising you that
you'll make, you know, X amount of
dollars. However, if you actually follow
what I'm about to show you in this
video, I'm pretty confident that you'll
start making sales online as I've seen
that happen across many of my students.
Now, if you're wondering what product
we'll be selling, we'll be selling
ebooks. Because in my opinion, ebooks
are the best digital product, especially
for beginners to get started with. It's
super easy to create, especially with
AI. It has very high demand and it is a
huge industry. So we're going to keep it
super simple here. The entire business
plan comes down to three steps. All
we're doing here is to first find
something people already buy, then we
create a simpler version of that, and we
put it where buyers already are hanging
out. So, step one is a very simple yes
or no question. Are people already
buying books on this topic on Amazon?
So, first we want to come up with a
bunch of book topics. So, you want to do
a huge brain dump here. Come up with a
list of your hobbies, interests,
passion, and whatever cool book topics
that you can think of. Then we're going
to take that and put it into Amazon, and
we will start searching for Amazon's
book category. And we're going to look
for books already selling on the topic.
If you find a bunch of books selling on
the topic, then that means that yes,
that is a profitable topic. So, I'm
going to take this to Claude here and
just ask a very simple prompt, "Give me
50 profitable book topics I can write
about." And this is what we got. We got
intermittent fasting for women over 40,
air fryer, sourdough baking, anxiety
workbook, ADHD productivity,
Mediterranean diet meal prep,
self-discipline, stoicism, and so much
more. Now, that's just one way of
getting ideas. Obviously, you can come
up with these ideas on your own as well.
But one of the idea that came up was how
to stop overthinking. So, I'm going to
take that exact topic and go to Amazon,
sort by books category here, and I'll
type that phrase here and click enter.
And these are the books that shows up on
page one. So, what you want to do is
open each one like this. And once you
get to the product page, you scroll all
the way down once you find the product
details, and you'll find a section that
says bestsellers rank. This is Amazon
telling us how well this book is selling
compared to other books. So, if it says
number one in the bookstore, that means
it's the number one best-selling book in
the entire bookstore. If it's number
100,000, then it's the 100,000
best-selling book in the entire
bookstore. So, when it comes to
bestsellers ranked, the lower the
better. In this case, this is an
audiobook. It's the 41st best-selling
audiobook right now in the audiobook
store, which is really good. But that is
for audiobooks. We can actually turn our
ebooks into paperback audio, so we do
want to factor in how much those books
are selling. But you can simply switch
over to the Kindle format or the
paperback format to check the
bestsellers rank for those different
formats. As you can see, the Kindle
version is selling really well.
Generally, we're looking for books below
80,000 BSR, especially in the paperback
books. I know we're talking about
selling ebooks, but once again, it's
very easy to convert that ebook into a
paperback, audio, and make a lot more
money. So, I like to do my topic
research in the paperback version of the
book. So, this is way below 80,000. It's
189. It's selling extremely well.
There's another book, this one, selling
extremely well as well at 312 in the
books category. And you see that many
other books like this one and this one
is also below 80,000. Now, I'm seeing
this number because I have a free Chrome
plugin called DS Amazon Quick View. So,
you can go to the Chrome Store, download
this. Essentially, it just shows you the
BSR right on the search results, so you
don't have to open each book up, scroll
down to the the product details, and
then see the best sellers ranked there.
So, this is how you can confirm that the
topic is profitable before you start
writing because that is very, very
important. You don't want to waste a lot
of time, you know, creating a book that
nobody's interested in. It's not
selling, right? So, you don't want to
come up with a brand new topic. You just
want to go off of proven topics that are
already selling and make your own
version of it. Now, you can definitely
write about your passion, but you still
got to check if whatever you're
passionate about is actually selling on
Amazon. Because if your passion is in a
profitable topic, that's the best case
scenario. But, if you're trying to make
money and the topic that you're
passionate about has zero demand, it's
not selling, then that's not a very
smart business move. And that's when you
have to decide, do I want to follow my
passion that's most likely not going to
make you money, or am I doing this for
business and trying to make money? Which
means that you have to follow demand.
So, once we've identified a profitable
topic here, we move on to step two,
which is to create a simpler version of
it. Now, when I say simpler, I'm not
saying a inferior product, right? I'm
not saying just whip up a, you know, bad
quality book, put it up on Amazon.
That's not what I'm saying. Sometimes
simpler is better. Sometimes people
value, you know, books that are short,
to the point, get to the information
that they need as quickly as possible.
So, even if you have less pages, even if
your book is shorter, if you help the
reader get to their desired goal
quicker, that alone is value and it's
worth paying for the book. So, this is a
one-day project. You should be able to
write a book in one day. You know, even
if it takes a little bit longer, I would
not spend more than a couple days on
this. Maybe if you're a perfectionist,
max 1 week. But anything longer than
that, again, you're just being a
perfectionist and you're basically
self-sabotaging your progress by being
too much of a perfectionist, okay? Very
important to understand that you're not
writing a masterpiece here and your goal
is not to solve every single problem in
your topic. It's to solve one problem, a
very, very specific problem, clearly.
So, let's say you have a weight loss
book. You want to focus on one specific
method, one specific problem. So, it
could be something like how to lose
weight with intermittent fasting and you
only solve that one problem. You're not
going to talk about 10 different weight
loss method and cover so many different
things for so many different people,
right? You're going to focus on one
thing, which is intermittent fasting and
perhaps even for one audience, perhaps
for women over 50, right? So, it's going
to be super specific. Intermittent
fasting for women over 50. And that
focus is also something that's going to
make your book valuable and stand out
compared to all the other generic books
out there. So, the recommended length, I
would recommend staying between 10 to
15,000 words. Not because this is the
magic formula to this, it's just that
10-15K words is a nice place to be at.
If you want to go longer, that's
completely fine. But again, you're not
trying to create a masterpiece. It's
we're just trying to get a good enough
book out there so that we can start
making money online as quickly as
possible. Now, when it comes to how to
create a high-quality book fast,
especially if you're not a writer, the
best AI software is called coauthor.ai.
This is the software that I created
myself after being in this industry for
basically 10 years, knowing exactly how
a high-quality book should be
structured. I basically put all of that
into my own custom AI so it knows
exactly what to do. And you can work
with coauthor to create a high-quality
book super fast. So, if you do want to
check out coauthor, I'll leave a link in
the description. I am also coming up
with a bunch of different tutorials on
how to use Co-author to, you know,
create books. So, you can definitely
watch those, but it is a paid software.
So, for the purpose of this video, I'm
going to show you the free way of doing
this. So, going back to Claude, I asked
it, "Let's go with the topic of how to
stop overthinking. Please list out the
biggest pain points of this target
audience." It's very important to
understand what are the pain points of
your target audience before you actually
start writing the book. So, we got these
options, right? Lying awake at night,
replaying conversations from earlier
that day, week, or even years ago.
Mentally rehearsing worst-case scenarios
that almost never happens. Reading way
too much into texts, emails, and tone of
voice, and so much more. By the way, I
am using Opus 4.7, which I believe is
only included in the Pro plan. I think
it's 20 bucks a month. If you don't have
this, you can use, you know, once again,
the free version of AI. Just understand
that, obviously, the free version is not
as smart, which means you might run out
of credit, and, you know, you have to
come back the next day. So, obviously,
if you can get a Pro subscription, or,
you know, even better, if you get
Co-author subscription, that will speed
things up a lot more. But again, we're
working with what we have, right? So, if
you can only afford the free one, if you
want to do everything for free, just use
a free model. You can still use the same
prompts and keep going from there. So,
I've listed out a couple pain points
that I like, and I really want to solve
in my book. So, I pasted that back into
the chat, and I said, "Here are pain
points that I think we should focus on
solving. Based on this, please create a
detailed book outline for this book."
And this is what we got. So, it came up
with a full book title right here.
Obviously, you don't have to go with
that. You can, you know, come up with
something on your own as well. But we
got the introduction, the exhausting
loop you can't seem to escape, opening
hook, what overthinking actually is, the
hidden cost of living inside your own
head, why just stop thinking about it
has never worked for you, and part one,
chapter one, why your brain won't shut
off, chapter two, the six faces of
overthinking, chapter three, when
thinking feels safer than doing, chapter
four, stop second-guessing every
decision you make, and on and on until
the end. So, I think this is pretty
good. I think this is very detailed.
Obviously, if you don't like any of
this, you can change it, right? This is
just a suggestion. AI is just an
assistant. It's not a replacement. So,
you want to work with AI and, you know,
go back and forth until you're happy
with the outline, until you're happy
with what you are going to cover inside
the book. Before we actually start
writing the book though, I want to
finalize the book title. So, I asked
Claude to give me 10 title ideas for
this book. Give me versions of titles
that are clear, but also catchy. Because
Claude gave me just the title how to
stop overthinking initially, right? So,
I wanted to come up with different
versions. Now, you don't want to be too
fancy with your title. It has to still
be clear, and that's exactly why I said
give me versions of titles that are
clear, but also catchy. If you can come
up with a cool, you know, catchy title
that is also very clear on what your
book is about, that is the best balance.
What you don't want to do is something
like this. Like unstuck, right? It's
catchy, but you have no idea what your
book is about, and that is a huge
mistake people make when it comes to
creating book titles. It still has to be
very clear on what your book is about,
okay? So, like this one, stop
overthinking everything. A little bit
catchier than how to stop overthinking,
but it's still very clear that this is a
stop overthinking book, right? Same as
this, the overthinker's escape plan.
Quiet the noise. A little bit more
vague, you know, so I don't like it as
much as these ones, but a little bit
better. The 2:00 a.m. mind, I think it's
a little too catchy, but out of your
head, I think it's okay. The end of
overthinking, that is good as well. And
stop living in your head, I think that
sounds pretty good, too. So, I went with
stop overthinking everything, a
practical guide to quieting your mind
and trusting yourself again. So, I said,
let's go with this. Please write the
introduction chapter. And there we go.
So, we got the introduction chapter.
It's 2:14 a.m. You've been lying in bed
for hours. Your body's heavy, your eyes
burn from being open too long, and yet
your mind is sprinting. You're replaying
a conversation from earlier today, then
one from last week, then somehow one
from 7 years ago that you haven't
thought about in forever, but it's
suddenly playing in 4K resolution behind
your eyelids. Now, I think that is
pretty good. Obviously, we don't want to
just copy-paste from AI. I also want to
acknowledge the fact that again, I'm
using Opus 4.7, which is the smartest
Claude model, which I think you got to
pay 20 bucks a month for. And Opus is
pretty expensive, so you might run out
of credits, you know, for the day, and
you might have to come back the next day
if you're using this, or you can use
coauthor.ai. The writing is just as
good, but, you know, you're not going to
run out of credits. So, that is an
option as well. What you want to do here
is to obviously read through the entire
chapter, okay? And you want to edit the
chapter and change up some content here
and there, add your own personal
stories, you know, add the way you talk
into the text. And by the way, you can
do this in a Google Doc, so you can just
copy this, paste it into Google Doc,
start editing it, and once you're happy
with that, you can move on to the next
chapter. Again, very important to
understand, you don't want to just
copy-paste from AI. We're not publishing
100% AI-written books, right? We're
using AI to speed up the process of
writing our own books, which means we
have to add our own inputs. We have to
add our own human touch. By doing so,
you can actually copyright your book,
too. You can copyright your book if you
actually humanize AI content. But if
you're just copy-pasting from AI, you
cannot copyright that, which is another
reason why we want to improve upon, you
know, what we get from AI. But
essentially, you just repeat this
process, right? You generate one
chapter, edit it, generate another
chapter, edit it. And typically, with
normal, you know, AI tools like Claude,
ChatGPT, Gemini, what happens is that
the introduction chapter is amazing,
chapter one is also amazing, chapter
two, chapter three, maybe it's okay, but
from, you know, around chapter three,
chapter four, it starts becoming
extremely repetitive because it doesn't
remember what it wrote earlier. And
again, you know, the tool is a generic
AI tool. So, it does everything decently
well, but it does nothing amazingly
well, because it's not trained
specifically to write books. So, as you
progress towards later chapters, you
might have to do more editing than
earlier chapters. AI, you know, quality
might drop. That's the state of AI right
now, especially with generic tools, once
again. If you don't want to deal with
that, if you'd rather just pay a little
bit, you know, to save a lot of time,
then again, coauthor.ai is an option,
but I'm not making this video to
basically just pitch coauthor, right? If
you want to check it out, you can, but
if you want to, you know, do everything
for free, you can, too. Just understand
that these are the cons of doing so.
These are the downsides. So, you're
investing more time, but again, you're
saving money. So, keep going until
you're done with the book. Again, you
can, you know, stop around 10 to 15,000
words. If you want to go longer, you
can, but it's completely up to you. Just
make sure that you're happy with the
book, you think it's, you know,
relatively high quality, but again,
don't go to the other extreme, which is
to be too much of a perfectionist and
you're spending months and months and
months doing this, okay? Balance is key
here. So, before you publish, you have
the option to create a pen name or a
real name, which by the way, it really
doesn't matter, you know, which one you
choose. So, both are allowed. So, you
want to just pick one and go for it. It
really doesn't affect sales, it really
doesn't affect branding, it does not do
anything besides whether you're okay
showing your real name or you just want
to you know, do this anonymously. The
next thing we want to do is to format
the book. So, formatting is essentially
making the book interior look nice. So,
when people do buy your book on Amazon
and they read it on their Kindle device
or maybe you create a paperback version,
so they have a print copy of it, the
text is aligned, the margins are set,
everything looks nice, right? And
presentable. So, it might seem
complicated, but once you learn how this
works, it's actually pretty simple. If
you have coauthor.ai subscription, you
know, we have a formatting tool that
does this basically automatically for
you. But if you don't have that, there
are free ways to do it. You can follow
this video. I'll leave a link to this
video in the description below. You can
follow it step-by-step and format your
book for free. Now, next is a fun part.
It's time to create your book cover and
you got some options here. Once again,
coauthor.ai creates premium AI covers as
part of the subscription, so you can go
and generate book covers there. Another
option is to use Canva or using free AI
tools. Again, we're not trying to be
perfect, so just keep it simple. I do
have a Canva book cover creation
tutorial here. The link is also in the
description below. If you would use free
AI tools, this is how it looks like. So,
I'm going to go to Chat GPT. You can do
this on Gemini as well. Claude is not
the best with images. As an example, I
asked it to generate a book cover for
the book that we just wrote, and this is
what we got, which is a not the best.
It's definitely not the best. Although
Claude themself, you know, acknowledged
that this is just a mock-up. For a
professional design, you should be using
other tools and whatnot. So, they are
being honest here, but again, it's not
the best when it comes to images. So,
instead of Claude, what I'm going to do
is to go to Chat GPT. I'm just going to
click on create an image over here and
just say, "Please create a book cover
for the book titled this." And this is
what we got. So, Stop Overthinking
Everything, Practical Guide to Quieting
Your Mind and Trusting Yourself Again.
Looks pretty good. I actually like this.
And Chat GPT does a pretty good job with
coming up with a book cover. The only
thing is with the free version, you get
like three generations, right? So, if
you want more, then you just got to pay
for the pro plan, which again, I think
is like 20 bucks a month. So, if you
start getting Claude pro plan, Chat GPT
pro plan, you know, another pro plan for
something else, you might as well just
get Co-author. I think it's simpler,
everything all in one place. But I want
to show you another version of this book
cover. So, I asked it to make it a
text-based cover, make the text the main
focus, and just use images or vectors
surrounding it as a complimentary
element. Because when it comes to like
self-help books, these text-based covers
are doing really well nowadays. So,
these realistic images type book cover
designs, you know, is kind of
old-school. It's not doing as well as
something like this. And as you can see,
it looks pretty nice. Once again, it's a
little hard to edit images if you want
to. With Co-author, we have a design
studio that it links to after this. So,
you can edit the cover from here. You
can also create a spine and a back
cover, so you can, you know, sell it as
a paperback as well. Which as I said in
the beginning of this video, the steps
you're taking to make your first couple
sales online and making your first
dollar online is not the same as the
steps you take to make 10K per month.
So, if you want to scale your business,
perhaps, you know, later on, invest in
Co-author, invest in, you know, more
tools, different steps. But the goal of
this video is to make your first dollar
online. For your first dollar online,
you don't have to be a professionist,
you just got to create something, get it
out there. And for that, I think this is
a good enough. All right, so we found a
profitable topic, we created the book.
Now, we move on to step number three,
which is to put it where buyers already
are. This is where most how to sell
digital products online, how to sell
ebooks online videos on YouTube get it
wrong. Everyone else tells you to create
a Gumroad store, build your own website,
start posting on social media, and get
those people to your website. To be
completely honest, that's not the best
way. It's actually a very, very slow
way, not effective at all, and most
likely those people are teaching you
that because they get sponsored by
Squarespace, they get sponsored by Wix,
they make money just making the video
and not actually doing the business
themselves. Because when you list a
product on your own website, your
website has zero traffic. So, again, you
have to post on social media, run ads,
get people to your website. But, instead
of trying to get people to come to you,
why not just go where people already
hanging out, where people are already
looking for things to buy? Which takes
us to step three. Once again, step three
is put it where buyers already are
hanging out, which most people in the
United States and also in other
countries buy books on Amazon. When
people think of buying books online,
they literally think of Amazon first
thing. Most of you watching this, I'm
sure that is the same. Amazon has huge
built-in traffic, millions and millions
of people looking for books to buy every
single day going to Amazon. So, by
listing your books on Amazon selling it
on Amazon, you don't have to deal with
making your own website. You don't got
to deal with inventory, you don't have
to deal with fulfillment, you don't have
to deal with customer service, which by
the way, if you use Wix, Squarespace,
Gumroad, Stand Store, all of that you
got to do yourself, it's more work.
Plus, you have to pay for those
services, right? But, by listing it on
Amazon, they handle everything. And
that's exactly why it is the most
beginner-friendly way to start selling
digital products online. So, when it
comes to how to upload your book on
Amazon, I do have a full step-by-step
tutorial. Once again, the link to this
video is in the description. It's a
simple 10-minute tutorial. You can
follow it and have your book uploaded on
Amazon. Once you upload the book, Amazon
will review your listing. If there are
any errors, you can go back and change
it. They'll let you know. But if no
errors, your book will be live and
selling on Amazon in 1 to 3 days, which
means you could be a published author
literally within few days after
uploading, which is very cool. Now, once
your book is uploaded and selling on
Amazon, in terms of how you check if you
made any sales or not, how you check how
much money you've made from the books,
you just go to your KDP account over
here, which I forgot if I mentioned
this, but Amazon KDP is a name of the
program that you sign up for to publish
your books on Amazon. Amazon KDP stands
for Kindle Direct Publishing. It is 100%
free to sign up, no monthly fees, no
sign-up fees, nothing. Amazon only takes
a small cut from your sale once you make
a sale. So, until you actually make a
sale, you're not paying Amazon anything.
And again, Amazon only takes cut from
the sale, so you never actually lose
money from this. So, anyways, once you
log into KDP dashboard, you go to
reports over here, and you can see right
here if you've made any sales, it will
show up right here. So, that was
actually for my second KDP account that
I've opened. I actually sold my first
KDP account for $820,000,
which is something that, you know, as
you scale this business, as you build it
up, your book portfolio is a sellable
asset. A lot of e-commerce business you
can sell, well, your books, your KDP
account is also kind of similar to
e-commerce. You can sell it for a big
amount if you want to. So, I sold my
first account for $820,000,
as you can see here. If you don't
believe me, if you don't believe
anything I say, I documented my entire
journey of building my own KDP business
in this playlist called KDP income
reports. It is on my channel. You guys
can go check it out. Now, I do have a
coaching program called Royalty Hero,
where I teach students how to do this,
and I want to show you some student
results here. Quick disclaimer, I'm not
guaranteeing any results. This is not an
income claim. This is not me telling you
that, you know, by joining the program
you're guaranteed you'll make X amount
of money because obviously it all
depends on how much work you put into
it. Also, these aren't typical results.
It's just what is possible. So, first we
have this student who published her very
first book yesterday. She woke up to
almost $40 in a single day. Now, I'll be
honest, this is not typical results, but
again, it's possible, right? The goal of
this video is to make your first couple
sales, your first dollar online. This
student over here made way more than her
first dollar, you know, from her first
book, but essentially the steps she took
is a little bit more detailed version of
what we took today. As I mentioned, this
video is a simplified version, you know,
in the program I teach a little bit more
detailed version, but even with a
simplified version, it should be enough
to start making sales online. Please
understand that I'm not guaranteeing
anything though. I just have to keep
repeating the no guarantees thing
because YouTube is very strict when it
comes to income claims nowadays, which
is a good thing because there are a lot
of channels that, you know, makes these
crazy promises. That is why I keep
saying this. We have another student
over here who made $161,000
his first year with just from 10 books.
And we have a lot more student success
stories. If you want to check it out,
you can check out our website. I'll
leave a link to roadtohero.com in the
description. So, that was the overview
of the process. You can go and follow
this and start publishing books on
Amazon using Amazon KDP, which I think
is the most beginner-friendly business
model out there. Once again, the goal of
this video was not to make 10K per
month, not to make millions of dollars.
It was just to start making couple sales
online, to make your first dollar
online. However, it's a stepping stone,
right? You start here and you start
making sales here, you start gaining
confidence that, "Oh my god, I can
actually make money online." Which was
exactly what happened to me, right? I
made my first dollar online from doing
this exact business, taking the exact
same step, and everything completely
changed. I just kept scaling from there.
Now I made millions of dollars online.
But everything starts from that one
small step. So, you start making some
sales here. Amazon is so huge that even
if you just take the whole upload and do
nothing approach, there is a pretty high
chance that you will start making sales
here and there. Obviously, not a
guarantee, but that's typically what we
see in the space. And as you start
making sales online, that is proof that
you can do this, right? You can actually
make money online. And what's stopping
you from taking this to 10k per month,
20k per month, a lot more is just simply
taking this seriously. And also adding a
little bit more steps to what we talked
about, right? If you want to make a
couple sales here and there, you can
just upload forget about it. Amazon can
help you sell your books. But when it
comes to making 10k per month more, you
probably have to supplement what we've
done here by creating a little bit of
longer book, you know, by marketing the
books yourself because although Amazon
markets the book, you also want to
market the book first, then Amazon will
recognize that this book is selling and
they'll push it more. So, there's a lot
of things when it comes to this business
that you can add on to and keep scaling
from here. So, stick to this plan for 30
days, watch your life change, watch
yourself making your first dollar
online, watch your confidence grow, and
keep going from there. To scale your
business from here, you can create
better books, you can publish more
books, eventually you can hire a team to
create books faster for you, you can
start running ads, you can expand into
different formats like paperback, audio,
hardcover. It's not the focus of this
video, but just understand that there's
a lot more to this business if you want
to make more money. I generally think
this is the best business for beginners
because you don't have to deal with
inventory, you don't have to deal with
shipping, you don't even have to deal
with customer service or tech issues
because Amazon handles everything for
you. All you got to do is repeat the
simple three-step process of finding
profitable topics, creating a good book
on it, and listing it on Amazon. If you
enjoyed this video, let me know by
leaving a like and subscribing because
that is the best way to let me know to
make more videos like this. If you want
to learn more about my digital
publishing coaching program, Road to
Hero, the link is in the description as
well as coauthor.ai
and all the videos and all the resources
that I mentioned throughout this video
is all in the description below. If you
made it all the way until the end, great
job for doing so. Let me know that you
made it all the way here by leaving a
fire emoji. I'll try to respond to as
many comments as possible. Thanks so
much for watching, and I'll see you in
the next one.